You don't want to throw a flour that is caked in there because it won't mix properly.
So, we sift it to get all of the hard stuff out of it if, if there is any hard stuff.
Normally, there is none.
And also, you incorporate air inside that flour, and that air gives it space, therefore it will mix much better inside the dough that you're trying to prepare.
So, we just just pour the flour in there.
Now, because this flour is arrogated, and it's sitting on top of the big chunk of butter and sugar, well, it has a tendency to just come out and be thrown out a bit.
So, expect a cloud there.
Because of that we turn off and on the oven, I mean the mixer.
We turn the mixer off and on constantly until the flour is kind of mixed in there so it will then be thrown all over the place.
This is the most important and most critical point of cookie making.
As soon as the flour is incorporated, the minute the flour gets inside of that mixture that you had in there, you want to stop the mixing process.
You want to stop the mixing process, otherwise you have over-mixed.
And if you over-mix, this step took only two minutes.
Maybe minute and a half, two minutes.
If you over-mix, as I mentioned before, you're going to incorporate air into your cookie dough and the cookie dough will run all over the place.
So, as some of the flour is inside your mixture of butter and your sugar and your eggs, you're ready to put your mixer on the off position and get the other ingredients, which is chocolate chips, inside your dough.